Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
"Great Detective Conan"
"Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi"
Ran...
Don't come in!
What is it?
It's okay, so come over here.
I can't move...
Eh?
This is...
Infra-red ray sensors?
Shin'ichi...
I can't stand anymore.
Ran, hang in there.
"Careful, Explosion"
Damn...
If I touch a sensor, there'll be a bang.
This date was...
"Beika City Bank
Safe-Deposit Boxes Floor"
"Close"
"Beika City Bank"
"System Development Dept.
Sonoda Machiko"
"The moment you report this to the police
This bank will blow up"
"Blow up"
"High School Student Detective
Kudo Shin'ichi"
"Beika City Bank, Safe-Deposit Boxes Floor"
There's no mistake that's Sonoda Machiko-san?
No mistake.
That cell phone's Machiko-chan's.
I recognize the strap.
What sort of acquaintance
was Machiko-san to you?
"Private Detective - Mori Kogoro"
Ran's computer school teacher.
And my drinking buddy.
We weren't doing anything dirty. All wholesome...
Oi!
"Branch Manager - Emoto Takeo"
That computer school is a
subsidiary of our company.
She held posts both here
and as a lecturer there.
That ringtone!
That's definitely Machiko-chan's.
"Mori Kogoro"
Machiko-chan, hang in there!
It's true.
Machiko-chan!
"The moment you report this to the police,
this bank will blow up"
Anyhow Branch Manager,
let's contact the police.
Please wait a moment!
What'll you do if it really does blow up?
Everyone here is saying
don't discuss this with the police.
By the way, what are you doing here
at the bank, Sir?
During the day today...
"Ah, Machiko-chan!
What is it?"
"Are you inviting me to a Go-kon?"
"I'm sorry."
"Truth is, I've gotten in some serious trouble
and was hoping to get your advice."
"This can never be told to the police.
You cannot tell them."
"So please, come to my desk at the bank."
Thinking back on it now, this must have been
the reason she said not to tell them.
And, when I guided Mori-san here...
...for some reason these shutters were closed.
Why do you say, "for some reason"?
This shutter is
totally controlled by computer...
...and isn't opened or shut at anytime
other than the scheduled hours.
Oi, what does this mean?
Most likely the criminal tampered with the
security system by hacking into its programming.
What's more,
they were able to plant a device...
...where the entire bank would blow up
the moment this panel is operated.
An inside job crime...
Each of the security camera videos
were checked on all the entrances and exits...
...but no intruders were seen going
either in or out of this building.
Who is currently left behind in this building?
Us and 2 security guards...
...and 3 others.
"Assistant Branch Manager
Nimura Yuzo"
"In Charge of Safe-deposit Boxes
Sakai Yoko"
"Corporate Sales Division, Chief Clerk
Hasegawa Ryosuke"
Which of you is the criminal?
Sir, that kind of question is...
Don't tell me it was all three of you?!
- You're wrong!
I alone killed her.
- That's wrong!
I did it.
Wrong! I'm the criminal.
Hello, Ran? Did it get there?
It's arrived, but...
"Police Headquarters, Conference Room"
Say, what do you want done with
the photos you attached?
Have Detective Sato take a look at them.
She'll understand what I want analyzed
as soon as she reads the contents of the e-mail.
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend - Mori Ran"
Yeah. Ah, wait, Shin'ichi!
Geez...
"MPD Investigation Unit One - Sato Miwako"
"MPD Investigation Unit One - Takagi Wataru"
"Photos"? What is this case about?
I'm not sure, but I think he wants you
to have these photos analyzed.
"The moment you report this to the police
This bank will blow up"
Blow up?!
Get under a desk...
Sato-san, hurry!
Ran-chan, you too...
What are you doing?!
How shameful!
I want you to tell the truth!
I've done something terrible.
I didn't intend to kill her.
She's dead. There's no doubt
since I'm telling you that I did it!
Why are you lying...
You're the one who's lying!
I'm certainly the one who killed her.
You're already too late.
If you open the shutter here or if the
police start to move and this bank blows up...
...you won't be able to recover her!
Who put this up here?
Ala, ala, ala?
They're all denying it.
Sir, let's divide them up for now
and listen to their circumstances.
Oh.
Let's put the screws on these guys
and kick their asses! Come!
"Suspect 1
Assistant Branch Manager
Nimura Yuzo's Deposition"
Truth is, I and Sonoda Machiko were trying
to keep our relationship quiet.
You were lovers?
At first we mutually promised it would
just be a businesslike relationship...
...but recently Machiko had been saying
she couldn't endure that any longer...
"Divorce your wife."
She was pressing me to marry her.
"I told you, that's..."
"I'll tell your wife EVERYTHING."
"Stop it, I said..."
"Wait... Ah!"
You're saying you killed her after reaching
the limits of her blind love for you?
It was bound to be like this someday.
If I hadn't done that...
...my family would have fallen apart.
That's what I was thinking...
By the way, was it you who
put up that poster, Nimura-san?
I don't know... anything about that.
"Suspect 2
In Charge of Safe-deposit Boxes
Sakai Yoko's Deposition"
That woman was the subject of dark rumors.
There were dark rumors about Machiko-chan?
That she was embezzling from the company.
That she was opening safe-deposit boxes
without authorization from the users...
...and taking out any precious goods.
They were collateral
for her financing schemes.
She would make investments using them...
...and, once she had made a profit,
would return the goods...
...keeping the profits for herself.
That's nothing to joke about!
The career I had built up for myself
was being ruined by that little girl!
That's why it was necessary for me to
convince her to stop before this became serious.
Since you have to take responsibility
for your subordinates...
...you could have been fired as well, right?
So you tried everything that you could.
Today as expected, she was returning goods
she had taken without authorization.
"Ala. I don't want to hear
any more excuses."
"Before you lose this bank's trust..."
"Before they lose trust in ME?"
"What a laugh."
"Should I dial 110 and expose myself?"
"Wait..."
If I had let her get away like that,
it could have gotten serious for me...
That's what I was thinking...
And she had realized that.
Did you put up that poster?
No.
But, I don't think it's a bluff.
What?
She was an excellent System Engineer.
With this system, intruders couldn't get past.
Moreover...
Even I don't know what
those safe-deposit boxes contain.
If you checked all of them...
...I couldn't deny the possibility that
one of them contains a bomb.
Then...
...it was Machiko who put it up?
That's what I think.
"Suspect 3
Chief of Corporate Sales
Hasegawa Ryosuke's Deposition"
"if you do as I say, you can make
a lot of money..." she said.
But...
...an emergency broke out,
so she wanted my cooperation.
Emergency?
She was taking precious goods
from the safe-deposit boxes...
...and using them to make money...
Our boss, Sakai-san,
had gotten wind of that...
And...
"I want you to kill me."
"Eh?"
"Of course, it's just a little play."
"A play?"
"Truth is, I'm borrowing something
right now for the collateral I need."
"An emerald necklace currently worth
about 260 million yen."
"260 million yen?"
"The Middle East ambassador of
the Cairid Kingdom deposited it."
"That necklace is something I've taken out
of the safe-deposit box for right now."
"However tomorrow, because his
business plans changed suddenly..."
"...the ambassador wants to take his
emerald necklace out before returning home."
"But I can't return the emerald that quickly."
"You understand, right?"
"If that safe-deposit box is opened,
it's over for us."
"That's why before then,
some big incident needs to occur..."
"...so that the shutter is closed
and can't be opened."
"How?!"
The ambassador has to return to his home
because he can't change his schedule.
When the time comes...
...he'll have no choice but to
return home for the time being.
In other words,
that poster is nothing but a bluff?
She would gain time because...
...they'd be too afraid to make it a
police matter and too scared to open the shutter.
Then, you're saying... she's still alive?
That's right.
She took sleeping pills
and is pretending to be a corpse.
By the time they wear off...
In other words, her plan is to
regain consciousness around 9 a.m...
...after the ambassador to Japan has left.
And...
...once she inputs the password,
nothing will happen.
Then she's the only one
who knows the password.
She's a scary woman.
If I hadn't gone along like this...
...it wouldn't be possible to stop her crimes.
Hasegawa-san, you were going to
play your part in Machiko-san's plan...
...wait for her to return the emeralds
and then file a complaint?
Afterwards,
I'd explain everything to the police.
What?! Machiko-chan is alive?
That's according to Hasegawa-san's story.
Machiko-chan! Hang in there!
I'll save you!
But Sir, it's all contradictory.
Contradictory?!
Both Sakai-san and Hasegawa-san said
that Machiko-san was embezzling.
"She was embezzling from the company."
"She was taking precious goods from the
safe-deposit boxes and making money from them..."
So the probability she was embezzling is high.
But, if as Hasegawa-san has said
and Machiko-san is playing dead...
...then that deposition contradicts
what Sakai-san said about killing her.
Even though Sakai-san herself
is saying she did kill her.
"Divorce her."
On the other hand, Nimura says
he killed her out of blind passion.
What on earth is going on?!
You normally wouldn't say you were
the one doing that.
Between the three of them, there must be
something the criminal had found convenient.
Something the criminal had found
convenient to them!
What is it?
Oh Ran, find out anything?
Shin'ichi, listen closely.
There's a red mark showing up on
Machiko-san's leg.
Most likely that's...
Eh? And?
Got it.
Oi! Where are you going?
Boy detective!
Oi!
"System Development Department"
It hasn't gone into Sleep mode.
"Wait in the basement safe-deposit box room
If I don't show up, e-mail me here"
"Machiko"
There's something unusual about Sir's
drinking buddy Machiko-san's e-mail address...
Damn!
Just a little more...
Sir, what are you doing?
Well, I thought I'd get that cell phone.
I thought we might be able
to find something out with it.
Where did you get that?
I grabbed a brace from
one of the plants over there.
This is wonderful, Sir.
This is great, Sir!
This had a hand in it.
Huh? Huh, huh, huh?
Really? That's right, isn't it?
I knew it!
For this great detective, Mori Kogoro, every
sort of closed-room trick is but child's play.
And? What's the trick?
I'll explain it later.
Huh?
An explosion?!
Didn't a detonator just start?
I thought so.
What did you just think?!
What's this about, boy detective?
The cell phone at
Machiko-san's foot isn't reacting.
But...
...an e-mail ringtone can
be heard from inside there.
That means there's another
cell phone somewhere in there.
Where in there?!
All of the mysteries are hidden in this number.
Fool! It'll explode!
That's dangerous!
This is regrettable, Machiko-san.
Ma... Machiko-chan!
Unfortunately, she's dead.
Poor thing...
Oi! She wasn't strangled.
Then what on earth
was the cause of her death?
I'll explain that later.
Sir, where's that sound coming from?
From here! I can hear it here!
Only one part is open.
Just like I thought.
Sir! Machiko-san should have
the master key. Search her!
Yeah!
Boy detective, I have it!
I know, Sir.
What the one and only...
...sad truth is.
I know who the criminal is.
Who is the criminal?!
I will explain that in order.
Sonoda-kun...
Sonoda-kun, this is enough.
It's time to stop your play.
Outsiders have learned this much about it.
It's not possible for you to hide from
your crimes any longer.
Sonoda Machiko-san is completely dead.
Eh?!
That's not possible!
That will contact the police!
It'll explode!
Don't worry!
We've already opened it once before.
It didn't explode,
nor did it contact the police.
Someone's been tampering with the system.
No...
What is this about?
The presumption of this bomb warning...
...was that it was to camouflage that
Sonoda Machiko-san was feigning to be a corpse.
In other words...
...this poster and Machiko-san
being murdered for embezzling...
...are two separate things.
Separate things?
That's right.
Half a year ago, Machiko-san,
who knew all about computers...
...was commissioned by this bank's senior
management to perform a top secret mission.
Top secret mission?!
In order to stop a fraud from
within the bank...
...her duty was to hack into the computers of
the entire bank staff and keep an eye on them.
To prove the truth about this...
...Machiko-san hid something
in this safe-deposit box in advance.
That was...
...this diary.
This diary contains an exchange
of e-mails between two people.
These are...
...the exchanges between
Sakai-san and Nimura-san.
The ones who removed the ambassador's
emerald from the safe-deposit box...
...was you two, wasn't it?
You two took the necklace out...
...and then approached Machiko-san
with a plan to camouflage it.
"Please! We'll do this!"
"If this is exposed, it'll not only mean the end
of the bank but an international incident as well!"
"Sonoda-kun. You're the only one
we can rely on. Help us!"
"I still have two little children. Please!"
"Hey! If you can just hold him off
until tomorrow, we'll put it all back!"
"Besides, once the emerald is returned,
no one will suffer any loss or be hurt."
"Sonoda-kun!"
Machiko-san, following your request...
...bypassed the security system,
changed the password and closed the shutter.
"I'm counting on you."
And, leaving this poster so the shutter wouldn't be
opened until after the ambassador to Japan had left...
...you testified to having killed Machiko-san.
But...
But we really didn't kill her!
It's true! We didn't kill her!
Because Machiko-chan was just faking
she had been killed...
...you thought you'd be safe in saying
you had killed her, didn't you?
Not wanting the ambassador
to enter the safe-deposit box room...
...you'd need a credible murder case
as well as a bomb warning to do that.
Nimura-san.
Your talk about having an affair with
Machiko-san was all nonsense, wasn't it?
Rather than adultery, you were in debt
for tens of millions of yen.
Did she write such things?
Therefore, in order to repay the debt,
you joined forces with Sakai-san, didn't you?
Were you out of your mind, Sakai?!
I didn't know about this!
You two are criminal embezzlers.
And, the criminal who murdered
Machiko-san was...
...you, Hasegawa-san.
What are you suggesting?
In this diary,
you were written up about separately.
As her lover...
...Machiko-san wrote about her feelings for you
and her dreams of the future with you.
You and Machiko-chan were engaged, right?
You were engaged, but you were seeing
another woman on the side as well.
A client company's daughter, isn't it?
But, Machiko-san believed in you.
That's why you were the only one she discussed
Sakai-san and Nimura-san's fraud request with.
Here's what's written.
"I'm so happy."
"He says we'll go to the police and have
Sakai-san and Nimura-san prosecuted."
Yet even so, you betrayed her.
What's more, in the worst way.
Hold on there!
This is just your own,
selfish line of reasoning.
Thing is, when I got here,
the shutter had already been closed!
How could I possibly have killed her?
You!
I'll show you how right now!
On Machiko-san's corpse,
there's a small red bleed mark.
Machiko-san wasn't strangled...
She was poisoned.
You hid a blowgun disguised as
a brace hidden here...
...in this shrub pot!
Most likely the dart was tipped with
a powerful nerve poison.
In order to kill her this way...
...you'd need to know in advance Machiko-san was
playing dead here from having taken sleeping pills.
Moreover, since the shutter was down...
...you could testify that you
couldn't have killed her.
Furthermore, the only person
who could use this secret room was...
In other words...
...that could only mean you, Hasegawa-san.
That's nothing but speculation.
It's not speculation!
I'm MPD Investigation Unit One's, Sato.
I'm Takagi of the same.
We had an analysis done of
the photo of the corpse.
From the circumstances of the corpse,
it's almost certain to be poison.
I just sent an e-mail to the address
shown on Machiko-san's desk computer.
But that isn't her cell phone that's ringing;
it's a different one.
What are you getting at?
Please listen closely.
You should know where
that ringing is calling from.
I don't know.
0924...
Does that ring any bells?
Machiko-san made a gesture here
of her faith in you...
...when she followed
Sakai-san's request to play dead.
She believed you would return here,
accuse those two of embezzlement...
...and then bring her back to normal...
But you used her love.
Taking advantage that she was playing dead...
...you killed her.
Tomorrow, September 24th,
is your birthday, isn't it?
The password which opens this shutter...
...is also the number of your birthday, "0924."
Don't spout nonsense.
Machiko-chan was only going to play dead,
but you didn't have to intentionally kill her!
To say nothing that you shouldn't use a bombing
trick to go ahead and kill someone yourself!
Machiko-san, after they had been successfully
charged with embezzling...
...wanted to give you this cell phone as
a present from out of this safe-deposit box.
The e-mail address for
this cell phone present...
...is a combination of your birthday,
"September 24th"...
...and your name, "Ryosuke."
"As now, and forever more
I will love you
Machiko"
"As now, and forever more..."
"...I will love you."
"Machiko."
"Happy birthday"
"Happy birthday."
Machiko-chan...
...believed in a worthless person like you...
...until the very end!
Why did you have to kill her,
you scum!
Machiko...
This was far too sad...
Hasegawa-san...
"Happy birthday"
"Birthday"
Ran!
Ran?
I see...
I know now.
Just why we are trapped in this room.
The criminal who did all this...
Ran...
...it was you.
"Ran is dead?!"
"Finally, Next Week
The Shocking Final Episode!"